ハア ハア ハア…
左手
My left arm!
It's still there?
あるよな
I went back again?
また戻ってきちまった
No, maybe I should say I made it back.
いや 戻ってこれたと言うべきか…
Oh, sorry. Good morning.
あ… ごめん おはよう
Right, I guess you don't remember me.
って… やっぱり
忘れられてるのか
Sorry for the trouble I've caused!
ご迷惑をおかけしました
ナツキ･スバル 再始動しまーす
Natsuki Subaru will now start over!
Oh, yeah. While we're at it,
what's the date and time?
ところで
今って 何日の何時？
This is my third "first day"
at the Roswaal mansion.
（スバル）
３度目のロズワール邸の初日
Think back to that chill.
あの寒気―
Does that mean I died in my sleep due to physical weakness the first time?
最初の死因は
寝てる間の衰弱死ってとこか
But the second time around,
だが ２度目は―
someone definitely attacked me.
襲撃者がいた
俺がやられたってことは―
And does the fact that I was killed
mean everyone else here is a target too?
屋敷のほかの奴らも
みんな 狙われていたのか
All because we're caught up in Emilia's
royal selection, just like at the loot house?
盗品蔵と同じ
エミリアの王選絡みで
But even if I know that, I have no proof to explain it or any way to avoid it.
けど それが分かっても―
説明できる証拠も
未然に防ぐ手段も―
俺の手の中にはねえ
And to top it all off, I didn't
even see their face or weapon.
おまけに 相手のツラも
獲物も見てない
My death was totally in vain.
犬死に全開じゃねえか
You're irritating me to death.
（ベアトリス）
死ぬほどうっとうしいから―
Stop it or be blown away.
It's your choice.
とっととやめるか
吹き飛ばされるか選ぶといいのよ
Oh, sorry. My bad.
（スバル）ああ 悪(わり)い悪(わり)い
But somehow, it's like walking in circles
helps turn the gears in my head.
でも こうやってグルグルしてっと
不思議と頭のほうも回るんだよ
Cut me some slack, okay?
大目に見てくれ
俺とお前の仲だろ？
We're tight, aren't we?
I suppose you have some strange idea
about our relationship.
ベティーとお前に
どんな関係があるのかしら
You do realize we've only met twice, right?
まだ２回しか会っていないのよ
Well, I'm not here to bother you.
まあ お前には迷惑かけねえよ
Just serve some tea
or something, and let me relax.
茶でも出して
ゆっくりさせてってくれ
I suppose I'd never serve you anything.
そんなもん 出るわけないかしら
Ugh, you're irritating me!
はーもう うっとうしいのよ！
What's that book you're reading?
（スバル）
それは何の本読んでんだ？
I suppose it explains how to get rid of a bug
that has sneaked into your room.
（ベアトリス）
部屋に入った虫を
追っ払う方法が書いてあるかしら
You've got a bug in the library?
書庫に虫湧いてんのか
最悪だな それ
Damn, that sucks.
What kind of bug?
どんなやつだ？
It's about time for you to leave.
そろそろ
出ていってもらうのよ
Your hands have stopped shaking,
手の震えも止まってるし―
so I suppose you've calmed down
enough to mask your fear.
怖いのも ごまかせるようになった
頃合いかしら
あ… バレてた？
You could tell?
And I suppose you were trying to hide it?
隠そうとしてたのかしら
It's quite irking to be treated
as a mere convenience.
そうそう都合よく扱われるのも
心外なのよ
Man, talk about cold-blooded.
優しくないね 全く
Thanks for the help, though.
でも助かった　また頼む
I'll be leaning on you again.
I suppose being relied
on is nothing but a bother.
（ベアトリス）
頼まれても困るかしら
If you understand,
don't come back again!
だからもう 来るんじゃないのよ
Shoo, shoo.
"Shoo, shoo"?
シッシッって… あっ
Wait, am I the bug you're
trying to get rid of!?
ひょっとして
さっきの虫って 俺のこと？
Get out of here this very instant!
もう とっとと出ていくのよ！
おわーっ！
おわーっ
I-I would've been a smear on the concrete
if not for this flower bed.
花壇が無かったら即死だったな
Um...
（エミリア）えーと…
（スバル）ん？
Do you mind if I ask if you're okay?
大丈夫って聞いていい？
Emilia-tan, that very kindness
is my one and only solace!
エミリアたん
その優しさだけが俺の癒しだよ
You know, Rem spread manure
in that flower bed yesterday.
その花壇 昨日レムが
動物のフンを肥料にまいてたのよね
（スバル）おわーっ！
Three-second rule! I got out in time!
That doesn't count, okay!?
３秒ルール
ノーカン ノーカンだよね？
If it helps any, they say this
kind of thing is actually lucky.
こういうのは 運がつくって―
幸運がつくのと
言い換える考え方があって
Emilia-tan is already shifting
into consolation mode.
すでにエミリアたんが
慰めモードにシフトしてる
パック 起きて
Puck, wake up.
（パック）
ふあー… おはよう リア
Morning, Lia.
Morning, Puck.
おはよう パック
Sorry to ask after you just woke up,
but could you wash Subaru off?
起きて いきなりなんだけど―
スバルの体
洗ってあげてくれる？
Subaru?
スバル？
Oh, I see. No problem.
ああ それじゃあ洗うよ
Here!
（パック）それ
（スバル）おえーっ！
There, all clean.
ほら きれいになった
Aren't you happy?
よかったね
（スバル）
オロ… オロオロ ロ…
I thought I was a goner.
死ぬかと思った
Wasn't there any other way to do that?
もっとほかのやり方
あったんじゃない？
You enjoyed that, didn't you?
何か楽しんでなかった？
No way! What makes you say that?
そんなことないよ プンプン
ニャー！
Punchback!
おかえしパーンチ！
シュ シュシュシュ…
Now you've done it!
やったな
Like that? It's my lethal move,
"Make the Cat Cry Ha Ha"!
どうだ 必殺 猫泣かせワキワキだ
Cut it out!
（パック）やめーい
Tail Punch!
尻尾パーンチ
これは 肉球グリグリだー！
You—
I'll finish you off with my Paw-Pad Grind!
Grind, grind, grind, grind!
（エミリア）
アハハハ アハハハ…
もう ごめん ダメ
Oh, gosh. Sorry, I can't...
What are you two doing?
２人して 何やってるの
ハ ハハ… お腹痛い
Ow, my stomach. Please no, I'm dying.
やだ 死んじゃう ハハ…
Well, now that I've one-eightied
from my initial bad impression...
とりあえず 最初の悪印象は挽回
Thank you for your assistance, Father!
アシストありがとうございます
お父さん
Who are you calling "Father"!?
誰がお父さんか
そう簡単に娘はやらんよ
I won't hand over my daughter that easily!
Please stop. You're both too funny.
やめて おかしいから
２人とも アハハハ…
Nothing beats your smile, Lia.
（パック）
リアの笑顔は最高だね
You agree too. Right, Subaru?
スバルも そう思うでしょ？
I totally do.
（スバル）超 思うよ
To me, Emilia-tan's smile is the first shining star in the night sky!
エミリアたんの笑顔は
俺には輝く一番星だ！
Not you too, Subaru.
もう スバルまで
Also, what does "tan" imply?
Where did it come from?
あと その“たん”て何？
どこから出てきたの？
It's what they call a pet name.
これは いわゆる愛称ってやつだよ
You know, like how Puck calls you "Lia."
パックがエミリアたんを
リアって呼ぶのと同じで―
It's an expression of affection
that shows how close we are.
親しい２人の間柄を示す
一種の愛情表現だな
I don't remember getting so close to you.
私 スバルとそんなに仲よくなった
覚えないんだけど…
It hurts how easily you said that,
but I won't lose heart!
地味に傷つく発言
だけど めげない俺
Think of it as an advance on our relationship.
関係の前借りだと思ってよ
It means I want us to get close enough
to call each other by pet names.
俺は愛称で呼べる関係になるくらい
親しくしたいと思ってるってこと
ＯＫ？
OK?
うん 分かった
それで納得してあげます
All right, I'll accept that.
Please. Stop staring at me.
イヤだ ちょっとこっち見ないで
I expected her to cringe,
but somehow got a positive response.
げんなりされるかと思ったら
好感触だよ？
What could this mean, Commentator Puck?
どゆこと？ 解説のパックさん
She doesn't have many friends,
うちの子 友達少ないから
so she longs for things such as nicknames.
呼び名とか そういうのに
飢えてるんだよ　チョロいの
She's an easy woman.
My main heroine is an easy woman, huh!?
俺のメインヒロイン
チョロいんだ！
Sister, Sister. In just a short time,
（レム）姉様 姉様―
ちょっと見ない間に
お客様がぬれネズミになってます
our guest has made himself
look like a drowned rat.
Rem, Rem. In just a short time,
（ラム）レム レム―
ちょっと見ない間に
お客様が汚いボロ雑巾だわ
our guest has turned
into a dirty, worn washrag.
Yeah, yeah. I look like a rat.
You don't have to tell me.
言われなくても ドブネズミに
なってんの 分かってるよ
Our lord, Roswaal-sama, has returned.
（２人）
当主 ロズワール様が
お戻りになられました
Please come inside.
どうぞ お屋敷へ
（スバル）ハア
Here we go.
きたな
My third "first meeting"
with the lord of the mansion.
３度目の初対面イベント
All I know for certain is that someone
will attack on the fourth night.
（スバル）
今 分かっていることは
４日目の夜に
何者かの襲撃があるという事実だ
I'd love to let them know that,
ロズワールたちに
それを伝えられればいいが―
but I can't explain
where I got the information,
俺は情報の出どころを
説明できねえし―
so they might think
I'm working with the assassin.
下手すると刺客の一味と
疑われかねない
If I knew even just my assailant's
physique it might be a different story.
せめて 襲撃者の背格好だけでも
分かれば―
話も違うんだろうが
So, this time, I'll use these next four days
だから今回は これから４日間―
to gather information
and learn who my assailant is.
情報収集に徹して
襲撃者の正体を暴いてみせる
And to that end...
そのためには…
Merely say the word.
（ロズワール･Ｌ･メイザース）
褒美は思いのまま―
You may have anything your heart desires!
さあー 何でも望みを言いたまーえ
In that case,
（スバル）だったら―
let me live here as a house guest,
俺を食客として―
and eat and sleep all I want!
この屋敷で
食っちゃ寝放題させてくれ！
（ラム）ふあー…
But how am I supposed to gather information?
とはいえ 情報収集って
何やればいいんだ？
I guess I'll start with some indirect questioning.
とりあえず それとなく
みんなから聞き込みをしてみるか
Hey, that's where I fell!
俺の落ちたとこ
Sorry to make you do this.
ごめん 迷惑かけて
Of course. If you'll excuse me, sir.
（レム）
はい 失礼します お客様
Huh? Wait...
I barely got a word in.
話す隙もねえ
I can't find anything out of the ordinary.
特に異常はないな
What are you searching for?
（ロズワール）
なーにがないのかね？
Oh, it's you, Roscchi.
（スバル）…って ロズっち
Don't scare me like that. It's misleading.
脅かすなよ
紛らわしいんだよ
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
Magic - died of weakness in sleep
Sound of chains
Roswaal's chains X
Misleading  !!
はーい
Come in!
Here you go, sir.
お客様 どうぞ
Oh, thanks. Wanna drink it with me?
（スバル）
あ… ありがとう　一緒に飲む？
No, thank you, sir.
結構です お客様
Hey, you can be a little friendlier
to me if you want...
って… もっと
気安く接してくれても―
かまわないんですけど…
Well, it's my first day.
I guess it makes sense.
まあ 初日だし こんなもんか
Yo!
You barge in here every day
without even knocking.
毎日ノックもせずに入ってきて
本当に 無礼極まりない奴なのよ
You truly have no manners whatsoever.
I suppose leaving before you get blown away would be in your best interests.
吹き飛ばされる前に とっとと
消えたほうが身のためかしら
Whoa! Wait, wait...
ちょっ タンマタンマ
I just want to ask you something.
お前に聞きたいことがあるんだよ
Is there any magic that weakens
and kills someone, as if putting them to sleep?
相手を衰弱させて―
眠ったように殺す魔法とかって
あったりする？
If I must answer, then yes, there is.
あるかないかで言えば あるのよ
There is?
あるのか
I suppose it isn't so much
magic as it is a curse, though.
（ベアトリス）
魔法というより
呪いのほうに近いかしら
There are many such things among
the spells that shamans specialize in.
呪術師が得意とする術法に
そんなものが多いのよ
Shamans?
呪術師？
Magicians.
（ベアトリス）
まじない師 転じて呪術師は―
However, shamans are a subclass
of magic- and spirit-art users
北方のグステコって国が発祥の
魔法や精霊術の亜種かしら
that I suppose originated
in the northern nation of Gusteco.
They're all quite useless,
and not to be taken seriously.
もっとも
出来損ないばかりで―
とても まともに
扱えたもんじゃないのよ
Though I suppose there is
an easier method than a curse.
でも 呪いよりも
もっと簡単な方法もあるかしら
Easier?
（スバル）簡単な？
I believe you've already experienced it.
お前はそれを
身を持って知ってるはずなのよ
Wait, you mean...
まさか お前…
That mana drain thing you forced
on me could actually kill me!?
あの強引なマナドレインって
死ぬ可能性があんのかよ！
Mana could be considered
one's very life force.
マナは生命力
そのものでもあるのよ
I suppose if it were continually sucked out,
you could eventually die of weakness.
それを強引に
吸い出し続ければ―
衰弱死させることだって
できるかしら
Wait... You're not the one
who killed me, are you?
（スバル）
まさか 俺を殺したの
お前じゃないだろうな？
Sorry to disappoint you, but I lead a busy life.
残念だけど
ベティーは忙しいから―
I couldn't even spare the effort to kill you.
お前を殺してやってる手間も
惜しいのよ
Is this the right one?
これでいいのか？
（ベアトリス）フン
（スバル）ああ えーと…
So, uh...
Oh, yeah.
ああ そう
Can anyone do that mana-sucking thing?
マナ チューチュー吸うやつって
誰でもできんの？
I suppose you couldn't
have phrased that worse.
その表現は 心外に尽きるかしら
In this mansion specifically, nobody
but Bubby and I can. Not even Roswaal.
屋敷だと―
ベティーと にーちゃぐらいで
ロズワールにもできないのよ
Wow, so it's actually a pretty rare skill, then.
へえ 意外とレアな
スキルなんだな
Don't suck up that stuff too much.
あんまし のべつ幕無しに
チューチューやるなよ
Especially from me.
特に 俺とか―
I'm really short on blood right now,
so I'd die in a heartbeat.
真面目に今は血が足りてねえから
あっさり衰弱死するぞ
Yes, all your organs were restored,
ああ モツは全部戻したけど―
but I suppose your blood wasn't replaced.
血までは戻らなかったかしら
Well, not that I had any
obligation to go that far.
まあ ベティーも
そこまでやってやる義理はないのよ
My organs?
モツ？　ん…
The way you said that
今の言い方だと―
makes it sound like you were
the one who healed my wounds.
何か 俺の傷口塞いだのが―
お前みたいな感じに
聞こえんだけど？
Trying to take the credit from
Emilia-tan makes you look bad!
エミリアの手柄 横取りとか
性格悪いぜ
I suppose you should know that silly girl
doesn't have the power to heal fatal wounds yet.
あの半端者の小娘に―
致命傷まで治せる力なんて
まだないかしら
Huh?
She and Bubby stabilized you,
and I healed your wounds.
にーちゃと小娘が
小康状態にした傷を―
ベティーが治してやったのよ
What!?
はあ？ な… マジで ウソだろ？
F-For real? You're kidding, right?
Of course. It's a lie.
フーン ウソか ウソなのか
ウソはよくないよ
It's just a lie! It's not nice to lie!
Lying is an absolute no-go!
ウソ ダメ 絶対ー
I suppose that's enough of your mouth.
やかましいかしら
嫌がりすぎなのよ
You're too averse to the truth.
I suppose a life not worth
saving should disappear!
治しがいのない奴は失せるかしら！
おわーっ！
Um...
（エミリア）えっと…
Once again, are you okay?
今日も大丈夫？
（スバル）
結局 キーワードは呪いと鎖
So, in the end, the key words
are "curse" and "chains."
I don't know anything else.
ほかはなんも分かんねえ
死に戻りの条件が
前と同じなら―
If Return by Death's conditions are the same,
I died three times in the capital,
and survived the fourth time.
王都のループでは３度死んで
４度目で突破できた
But that doesn't mean I intend to
treat this as a throwaway life.
だからって 今回を捨て回と
投げ捨てるつもりは毛頭ない
そのために エミリアの身辺を
気遣ってくれとパックには伝えたし
That's why I asked Puck
to keep an eye on Emilia for me.
（パック）
いいよ
いろいろと曖昧な話だけど―
Sure.
This is all really vague,
but I can tell you're asking
out of concern for Lia.
リアを案じてるのは
確かみたいだからね
（スバル）
４日目の朝 俺はここを出て…
On the morning of the fourth day,
I'll leave here and—
（ラム）
失礼するわ お客様
Pardon my intrusion, sir.
I see you really are studying, sir.
本当に勉強してるのね お客様
Wow, that's super rude.
お前 超失礼だな
I am a guest here, you know.
仮にもお屋敷のお客人ですよ 俺
食客という名の居候
そう認識しているわ お客様
You're a freeloader calling yourself a guest.
That's how I perceive it, sir.
Thanks.
ありがとう
うん やっぱマズい
Ugh, it's still nasty.
You'll incur the wrath
of the mansion's finest tea leaves.
お屋敷で出される最高級の茶葉に
バチが当たりそうな感想ね
Slacking off right in front of your guest?
客人の前で
堂々と サボりとか―
I have no words for that nerve of yours.
お前のクソ度胸には
言葉もねえよ
“もっと気安く”と
最初に言ったのは―
You were the one who told me
to be more friendly toward you.
お客様のほうでしょ
I'm only responding to your demand.
ラムはご要望に応えただけよ
それで？ 勉強は進んでるの？
So? How is your studying coming?
（スバル）まあな
Not too bad.
I can read simple fairy tales like these now.
これぐらいの童話だったら
読めるようになったぜ
微妙な常識観の違いを
楽しめて面白かった
It's interesting how the morals slightly differ
from those of the ones I know.
まさに 異文化交流したかんじ？
It's like true cross-cultural communication!
俺も 地元のおとぎ話
いくつか輸入してみようかな
Maybe I should import a few
fairy tales from my homeland.
「泣いた赤鬼」とか
Like "The Red Ogre Who Cried."
The Red Ogre Who Cried?
泣いた赤鬼？
何なら 話して聞かせようか？
Want me to tell it to you?
All right, your attention, please.
んじゃ ご静聴願おうか
むかーし むかし
あるところに―
Once upon a time, there lived
a red ogre and a blue ogre.
赤い鬼と青い鬼が住んでいました
The two were very good friends.
２人はとっても仲のよい
友達どうしでした
赤い鬼は 村の人間たちと
仲よくしたいと願っていました
The red ogre wanted to be friends
with the people of the village.
しかし 人は
怖がって近づこうとしません
But the people were too scared
to get close to him.
The blue ogre couldn't bear to watch,
見かねた青鬼は―
赤鬼のために
ある計画を思いつきました
so he devised a plan to help his friend.
"I'll make a ruckus in the village,
so you come and stop me.
僕が村で暴れるから
赤鬼くん 君が止めてくれよ
Then the villagers will be sure to trust you."
そしたら村の人は
きっと君を信用してくれる
計画は成功して―
The plan worked, and the red
ogre befriended the humans.
赤鬼は人間たちと
仲よくなれました
But as time passed,
something began to worry him.
しかし 日がたつにつれ
気になってくることがありました
His friend, the blue ogre,
no longer came to visit him.
それは あの日から
訪ねてこなくなった―
青鬼のことでした
ある日 赤鬼は
青鬼の家を訪ねてみました
One day, the red ogre went
to the blue ogre's house.
The door was tightly shut,
and a letter was affixed to it.
すると 戸が固く閉まっていて
張り紙が残されていました
そこには こう書かれていました
The letter said:
"Red Ogre, please have fun
with your human friends.
赤鬼くん 人間たちと仲よくして
楽しく暮らしてください
もし僕が このまま君と
つきあっていると―
If I continue to hang around you,
they might think you're a bad ogre too.
君も 悪い鬼だと
思われてしまうかもしれません
それで―
So I've decided to go on a journey,
旅に出ることにしました
けれども 僕はいつまでも
君を忘れません
but I will never forget you.
さようなら
体は大事にしてください
Goodbye. Please take care of yourself.
Your friend forever,
どこまでも君の友達
青鬼
Blue Ogre."
The red ogre read the letter
in silence, over and over again.
赤鬼は黙って何度も読みました
しくしくと涙を流して泣きました
Tears fell as he began to cry.
The end.
おしまい
（ラム）悲しいお話だわ
That's a sad story.
Yeah, it is.
そうだな
But I think it has a sweet side too.
でも 俺は優しい話だと
そうも思う
I'd say all the characters are just stupid.
（ラム）
登場人物に
バカしかいないんじゃないの？
と ラムは思うわ
赤鬼も青鬼も 村人たちも
The red ogre, the blue ogre,
and the villagers too.
That's kind of a harsh critique.
そいつはまあ 手厳しい感想だ
いや 俺も否定はしねえけどさ―
I mean, I'm not denying it, but...
That's why I both love and hate that story.
だから俺は この話が
大好きで大嫌いなんだよ
青鬼の自己犠牲は
すげえかっこいいけど―
The blue ogre's self-sacrifice
is really admirable,
but it's stupid because
he stood to gain nothing.
すげえ報われなくてバカだ
俺は頑張った分だけ
報われたいと思うタイプだし―
I'm the type of guy who wants
to be rewarded for my effort.
Is that what you think of the blue ogre?
お客様は青鬼をそう思うの
でもラムは 赤鬼のほうが
度し難いと思うわ
Still, I think it's the red ogre
who's beyond help.
自分の望みに
青鬼を巻き込んで 結果―
He dragged the blue ogre into his own desires.
As a result, he didn't lose anything.
Only the blue ogre did.
自分は何も失わずに
青鬼に失わせただけ
（スバル）
じゃあ お前は鬼２人は
どうすりゃよかったと思うんだ？
Then what do you think
the two ogres should have done?
赤鬼は 本気で人間と
仲よくしたいなら―
If the red ogre truly wanted
to befriend the humans,
he should have broken off
his horns and gone to them.
角でも折って
人里へ下りればよかったのよ
青鬼が見ていられなくなる前に
身を切るべきだった
He should have done that before
the blue ogre couldn't bear to watch anymore.
That's a pretty extreme opinion you have there.
（スバル）
そりゃまた随分と
極端な意見だな おい
Is it really?
そうかしら
Which of the two ogres would
you rather be friends with?
お客様は 鬼２人の
どちらと仲よくしたいと思うの？
鬼２人の？
Which of the two?
The red ogre, who can only wish
and be taken care of by others,
（ラム）
願うばかりで
尻拭いは人任せの赤鬼と―
自己犠牲に浸る バカな青鬼と
or the stupid blue ogre,
who basks in self-sacrifice?
つまらない答え
What a foolish answer.
If you want to befriend both,
どっちとも仲よくしたいだなんて
お客様は浮気症で優柔不断ね
you must be the indecisive, adulterous type.
You'll regret it one day.
いつか後悔するわ
I don't recall it being that kind of story!
（スバル）
そういうお話じゃなかったと
記憶してるんですけど？
Putting aside your homeland's fairy tales,
お客様の故郷の
おとぎ話はともかく―
こちらのお話で
印象に残ったものは？
did any of our stories
leave an impression on you?
Well, the ones that interested me most
（スバル）そうだな
気になったのは やっぱり―
were the middle one about the dragon,
and the one at the end about the witch.
この真ん中にあった
ドラゴンの話と 巻末の魔女の話だ
I finally know where the name
"The Dragon's Kingdom of Lugunica" comes from.
親竜王国ルグニカの名前の由来
やっと分かったよ
（ラム）そう
Oh?
It said the royal family signed
a covenant with a dragon,
（スバル）
王族と竜の盟約だなんて
書いてあったし―
こりゃ おとぎ話ってより
昔話だよな
so it's more like a folktale
than a fairy tale, right?
Yes, since it's true.
（ラム）
そうね 事実だから
The noble dragon still protects
this nation from far away,
今も尊きドラゴンは
この国の安寧を はるか遠方―
大ばくふのかなたより見守っている
beyond a great waterfall.
王家と交わした約束
その成就の時まで
It will do so until its contract
with the royal family is fulfilled.
あれ？
ドラゴンと約束した一族って―
Wait, didn't the royal family that
signed the contract recently die out?
つい この間 滅んでね？
そうね わりとあっけなく
Yes, quite abruptly.
No one knows what the dragon wants.
竜が何を求めているのか
それは分からない
今の状況で竜がどう動くかは
神のみぞ…
In the nation's current situation,
only the gods know—
No, only the dragon knows
what the dragon will do, sir.
いえ 竜のみぞ知るってところだわ
お客様
（スバル）ふーん
Oh, by the way, about this witch story—
あっ そうだラム
この魔女の話って…
I don't want to discuss that.
（ラム）
その話はしたくない
（スバル）え？
（ラム）長居しすぎたわ
I've stayed too long.
I'll come again to notify you
when dinner is ready, sir.
お客様 夕食の時に
また呼びにあがります
O-Okay.
That story you told me about the ogres...
さっきのお話―
鬼のことだけど
レムには聞かせないでちょうだい
Don't tell it to Rem.
I'm certain she wouldn't like it.
あの子はきっと
嫌がるお話だから
“怖い魔女 恐ろしい魔女
その名前を呼ぶことすら恐ろしい”
"A scary witch, a terrifying witch.
To even speak her name sparked up great fear.
Instead, everyone called her
“誰もが彼女をこう呼んだ―”
“嫉妬の魔女と”
the Witch of Envy."
ホントに大丈夫？
Are you sure about this?
竜車を呼んでもらって
王都まで乗っていっても…
We could call a dragon carriage
to take you to the capital.
I'll be fine.
大丈夫だって
いずれ エミリアたんに
ふさわしい―
One day, when I'm the kind of strong,
smart, rich man who's worthy of you,
強くて賢くて
金持ちな男になった時には―
I'll take you away on a white horse.
白馬に乗って
君をさらいに来るよ
Do you have a handkerchief?
ハンカチ大丈夫？
飲み水とラグマイト鉱石と―
Then there's drinking water,
lagumite ore, and...
それから それから
１人でさみしがらずに寝れる？
Will you be able to sleep by yourself?
Do you think you're my mom!?
（スバル）
完全にオカン目線？
Very well then, Subaru-kun. Take care.
そーれじゃ スバルくん
息災で
And do not lose the gift I gave you.
お土産も失くさないように
I added something equivalent to our
three days' worth of memories together.
君との３日間の思い出の分だけ
ちょこーっと上乗せしたから
口止め料だろ？ 分かってるって
Hush money, right? Don't worry, I get it.
余計なことは言わない
ドラゴンに誓うぜ
I won't say anything I shouldn't.
I swear to the dragon.
Talking with you makes any evil
scheme seem to lose its purpose.
君と接してると 悪だくみのかいを
見失いそうになるね
Also, in this nation, swearing to the dragon
is the highest form of promise.
それに この国で
ドラゴンに誓うというのは―
最上級の誓いだ
Be sure to keep that in mind.
ゆめゆめ それを忘れないように
了解
Roger that!
２人にも超世話になった
You two helped me out a ton.
特にレムりんは
いつもうまい飯をありがとよ
Especially you, Rem-rin.
Thanks for all the great food.
And Ram-chi...
ラムちーは… うん
Yeah! You're good at cleaning toilets, right?
トイレ掃除とか上手だよな
Sister, Sister. Our guest
is hopelessly bad at flattery.
（ラム）
姉様 姉様 お客様ってば―
お世辞が絶望的に下手くそですよ
（ラム）
レム レム お客様ってば―
Rem, Rem. Our guest has
a fatal lack of skill in flattery.
お世辞が致命的にセンスがないわ
Oh, shut up!
（スバル）
やかましいな
マジで思いつかなかったんだよ！
I seriously couldn't think of anything!
でも ありがとな
Thanks, though.
（ラム）ええ
（レム）はい
Yes, sir.
Subaru!
（エミリア）スバル
（スバル）お…
いろいろありがとう
何かあったら いつでも寄ってね
Thank you for everything.
If you ever need something,
you're welcome anytime.
Got it!
おう
エミリアたん ありがとー！
Thanks, Emilia-tan!
All right, here we are.
よし ここだ
特にエミリアの部屋がよく見える
I can see Emilia's room
especially well from here.
Now all that's left is to wait
for something to happen...
あとは―
事が起こるのを待ち構え―
and stop it.
食い止める
こんな使い方して
怒られるだろうなあ
She'd probably get mad
at me for using it this way.
怒られてえなあ
I hope she does.
死にたくねえな
I don't want to die.
死なせたくねえな
I don't want them to die.
What did I tell you, Natsuki Subaru?
言ったはずだぜ
ナツキ･スバル
Even if no one remembers what happens when things repeat,
繰り返した時
みんながそれを忘れていても―
お前はそれを覚えてる
you alone will remember.
Now that I think about it,
I didn't go shopping for Rem this time.
そういや 今回は
レムの買いだしがなかったな
純粋に俺の食材が浮いたからか
Maybe because the food meant
for me was leftover?
We still have a while to go before dark.
（スバル）
日没までまだあるってのに
Focus! Focus!
集中だ 集中
おわっ！
緊急脱出…
Emergency escape!
見た　ああ 見たぞ！
I saw it!
Yes, I saw it!
鎖の音の正体！
I saw the source of those chain sounds!
But it followed me here?
しかし こっちに来たか
（スバル）
完全に 相手の手のひらの上で
踊らされたってことか
Does that mean I played right
into my assailant's hands?
来るなら来いや
If you're gonna come,
then come at me!
根性 入ってるかー！
Do you have the guts!?
Now, show yourself, damn it!
さあ 姿を見せろ
クソ野郎！
I've gone through all kinds
of hell to see your face!
そのツラ見んのに
散々苦労したぞ コラ！
Very well, I shall.
（女性）
しかたありませんね
何も気づかれないまま―
The ideal scenario would have been
to finish this without being noticed.
終わってもらえるのが
一番だったんですが
You've gotta be kidding me.
ウソだろ…
Rem?
レム
The  Soundof   Chains